Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪I plant miles of peach blossoms just for her♪
أزرع أميالاً من أزهار الخوخ خصيصاً من أجلها
♪Sweet words bloom upon those branches♪
♪تزهر الكلمات العذبة على تلك الأغصان♪
♪Love runs deep, trapped in longing♪
♪الحب عميق، محاصر في الشوق♪
♪Night listens answers to longing are the most terrifying♪
♪تستمع الليل إلى إجابات الشوق، وهي الأكثر رعباً♪
♪At my fingertips, worries drift and linger♪
♪على أطراف أصابعي، تتلاشى الهموم وتستمر♪
♪Having tasted a moment of carefree joy♪
♪ بعد أن تذوقت لحظة من الفرح الخالي من الهموم ♪
♪Today, I pluck romance and moonlight♪
اليوم، أقطف الرومانسية وضوء القمر
♪And weave them all into a painting♪
♪ واجمعها كلها في لوحة ♪
=The Ultimate Vow, Unknown to You=
=العهد الأسمى، الذي تجهله=
=Episode 15=
=الحلقة 15=
Your Majesty. For generations, the Su family has given their lives to the Mobei royal family.
جلالتكم. على مرّ الأجيال، كرّست عائلة سو حياتها لخدمة العائلة المالكة في موبي.
The old General fought through blood and battle
خاض الجنرال العجوز معارك دامية.
on the northern frontier for more than twenty years.
على الحدود الشمالية لأكثر من عشرين عاماً.
Yet now,
لكن الآن،
his only bloodline
سلالته الوحيدة
has been killed by the first prince.
قُتل على يد الأمير الأول.
The thirty thousand soldiers of the Su Army
ثلاثون ألف جندي من جيش سو
were all forged by the old General himself, blade by blade and spear by spear.
جميعها صُنعت على يد الجنرال العجوز نفسه، نصلاً نصلاً ورمحاً رمحاً.
We kneel before Your Majesty
نحن نركع أمام جلالتكم
and beg leave to lay down our armor and return to our fields.
ونرجو الإذن بخلع دروعنا والعودة إلى حقولنا.
Yuwen Que!
يووين كيو!
I raised you into the man you are today.
لقد ربيتك حتى أصبحت الرجل الذي أنت عليه اليوم.
And yet you show such utter disregard for ruler and father alike.
ومع ذلك، فإنك تُظهر استهتاراً تاماً بالحاكم والأب على حد سواء.
Your Majesty, please restrain your anger.
يا صاحب الجلالة، أرجو منك ضبط غضبك.
If I may be so bold, I wish to offer a suggestion.
إذا سمحتم لي بهذه الجرأة، أود أن أقدم اقتراحاً.
Speak!
يتكلم!
From what I have learned,
بحسب ما تعلمت،
the first prince has always acted for the good of the realm.
لطالما تصرف الأمير الأول من أجل مصلحة المملكة.
As for the stabbing of General Su,
أما بخصوص طعن الجنرال سو،
it was incited by the performer Shen Qingru.
وقد حرض على ذلك الفنان شين تشينغرو.
No one knows what kind of wicked sorcery Shen Qingru used on the first prince.
لا أحد يعلم نوع السحر الشرير الذي استخدمته شين تشينغرو ضد الأمير الأول.
With just a few words,
ببضع كلمات فقط،
she set two great pillars of the court against each other.
لقد وضعت اثنين من أركان المحكمة العظيمة في مواجهة بعضهما البعض.
Such depth of scheming,
هذا العمق في التخطيط،
such venomous methods,
مثل هذه الأساليب السامة،
are truly abhorrent.
إنها بغيضة حقاً.
So this is her craft of sowing discord.
إذن هذه هي مهارتها في زرع الفتنة.
That Shen Qingru
ذلك شين تشينغرو
deserves death by a thousand cuts.
يستحق الموت بألف جرح.
We beg Your Majesty to see the truth and grant Shen Qingru death,
نرجو من جلالتكم أن تنظروا إلى الحقيقة وتمنحوا شين تشينغرو الموت.
to appease the spirit of the old General in heaven.
لاسترضاء روح الجنرال العجوز في السماء.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Issue the order.
أصدر الأمر.
Execute the rebel at once,
أعدم المتمرد فوراً.
Shen Qingru.
شين تشينغرو.
Your Majesty is wise.
جلالتكم حكيمة.
Long live our Emperor.
عاش إمبراطورنا.
By the Mandate of Heaven,
بأمر من السماء،
the Emperor decrees.
يصدر الإمبراطور مرسوماً.
Shen Qingru sowed discord,
شن تشينغرو زرع بذور الشقاق،
causing a meritorious official's death.
تسبب في وفاة مسؤول جدير بالثناء.
Her crimes warrant execution.
جرائمها تستوجب الإعدام.
She is to be beheaded today
سيتم قطع رأسها اليوم
to restore order to the court.
لإعادة النظام إلى المحكمة.
So decreed.
صدر هذا القرار.
Who dares touch her?
من يجرؤ على لمسها؟
I order you, as the first prince,
أنا آمرك، بصفتك الأمير الأول،
release Shen Qingru at once.
أطلقوا سراح شين تشينغرو فوراً.
Your Highness, I only act on orders.
يا صاحب السمو، أنا لا أنفذ إلا الأوامر.
Please do not put me in a difficult position.
أرجوكم لا تضعوني في موقف صعب.
Anyone who touches my woman
أي شخص يمس امرأتي
will pay with his life today.
سيدفع حياته ثمناً لذلك اليوم.
Your Highness, you must not.
يا صاحب السمو، لا يجوز لك ذلك.
Forcing this now will only doom her.
إن إجبارها على ذلك الآن لن يؤدي إلا إلى هلاكها.
Endure it for the moment.
تحمل الأمر في الوقت الحالي.
When His Majesty's anger subsides, we will find another chance to save her.
عندما يهدأ غضب جلالته، سنجد فرصة أخرى لإنقاذها.
Take her away.
خذها بعيداً.
Ru.
رو.
Do not be afraid.
لا تخف.
I will protect you at all costs.
سأحميك مهما كلف الأمر.
Protect me?
هل تحميني؟
Is this your protection,
هل هذه هي حمايتك؟
pushing me step by step
يدفعني خطوة بخطوة
into despair?
إلى اليأس؟
Go.
يذهب.
(Chengguang Hall)
(قاعة تشنغ قوانغ)
His Highness sent me to rescue you.
أرسلني صاحب السمو لإنقاذك.
So his conscience finally stirred.
وهكذا استيقظ ضميره أخيراً.
A pity it came too late.
من المؤسف أن ذلك جاء متأخراً جداً.
Do you still love him?
هل ما زلتِ تحبينه؟
I wish he were dead.
أتمنى لو كان ميتاً.
But if he dies,
لكن إذا مات،
would that not let him off too easily?
ألن يُسهّل ذلك عليه الأمر كثيراً؟
There are pursuers. We must go.
هناك مطاردون. يجب أن نذهب.
Stop.
قف.
♪I lift a strand of the brisk, pure wind♪
أرفع خصلة من الريح النقية المنعشة
♪And laugh at a lifetime bound by devoted love♪
♪والضحك على حياةٍ مقيدةٍ بحبٍّ مُخلص♪
♪Even with a single thunderous command♪
♪حتى بأمر واحد مدوٍّ♪
♪I have crossed bloodshed and roaring chaos♪
♪لقد عبرتُ سفك الدماء والفوضى العارمة♪
♪I cherish the grace within her gaze♪
أُقدّر الرقة التي تتجلى في نظرتها.
(Ru.)
(روسي)
(This time, I am letting you go.)
(هذه المرة، سأتركك تذهب.)
(Do not ever come back.)
(لا تعود أبداً.)
♪I plant miles of peach blossoms just for her♪
أزرع أميالاً من أزهار الخوخ خصيصاً من أجلها
♪Sweet words bloom upon those branches♪
♪تزهر الكلمات العذبة على تلك الأغصان♪
Young lady, we must leave now.
يا آنسة، يجب أن نغادر الآن.
♪Love runs deep, trapped in longing♪
♪الحب عميق، محاصر في الشوق♪
♪Night listens answers to longing are the most terrifying♪
♪تستمع الليل إلى إجابات الشوق، وهي الأكثر رعباً♪
♪At my fingertips, worries drift and linger♪
♪على أطراف أصابعي، تتلاشى الهموم وتستمر♪
♪Having tasted a moment of carefree joy♪
♪ بعد أن تذوقت لحظة من الفرح الخالي من الهموم ♪
♪Today, I pluck romance and moonlight♪
اليوم، أقطف الرومانسية وضوء القمر
♪And weave them all into a painting♪
♪ واجمعها كلها في لوحة ♪
(Bountiful Harvest, Cangzhou)
(حصاد ​​وفير، تسانغتشو)
You have not eaten properly for three days.
لم تتناول الطعام بشكل صحيح لمدة ثلاثة أيام.
I cannot eat.
لا أستطيع الأكل.
If this goes on, your body will give out.
إذا استمر هذا الوضع، فسوف ينهار جسمك.
Think of how many things still await you.
فكّر في عدد الأشياء التي لا تزال تنتظرك.
Perhaps this is for the best.
لعل هذا هو الأفضل.
One end to everything.
لكل شيء نهاية واحدة.
This kind of life,
هذا النوع من الحياة،
I do not want to live it anymore.
لا أريد أن أعيش هذه الحياة بعد الآن.
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
Are you punishing yourself, or punishing me?
هل تعاقب نفسك أم تعاقبني؟
Back then, you saved my life.
لقد أنقذت حياتي حينها.
Must I now watch you waste away like this?
هل عليّ الآن أن أشاهدك تذبل هكذا؟
Get up.
استيقظ.
I will eat.
سآكل.
General Su.
الجنرال سو.
The Cangzhou travel pass bears the military seal.
يحمل تصريح السفر الخاص بمدينة تسانغتشو الختم العسكري.
You may pass unimpeded.
يمكنك المرور دون عوائق.
(Command)
(يأمر)
Young lady, look, that sugar figurine stall is still there.
يا آنسة، انظري، لا يزال كشك تماثيل السكر موجوداً.
I remember you loved osmanthus sugar figurines the most.
أتذكر أنك كنت تحب تماثيل السكر المصنوعة من زهور الأوسمانثوس أكثر من غيرها.
I want to buy her freedom.
أريد أن أشتري حريتها.
Ten taels.
عشرة تيال.
Here is twenty taels.
هذا عشرون تيلًا.
Deal.
اتفاق.
See to her injuries as well.
اهتم بإصاباتها أيضاً.
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
If you had not saved me back then...
لو لم تنقذني حينها...
Take it.
خذها.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
I once believed
كنت أعتقد ذات مرة
that revenge was the only reason I stayed alive.
كان الانتقام هو السبب الوحيد الذي جعلني أبقى على قيد الحياة.
But now,
لكن الآن،
if I truly were to kill Yuwen Que,
لو أنني قتلت يوين كيو حقاً،
the two nations would go to war.
ستدخل الدولتان في حرب.
And these people...
وهؤلاء الناس...
Young lady...
يا آنسة...
Perhaps
ربما
it is time for me to let go.
حان الوقت لأتخلى عن الأمر.
Cui Di?
إله من؟
Do you remember me?
هل تتذكرني؟
Back then, in that alley by the East Market, we even got into a fight.
في ذلك الوقت، في ذلك الزقاق بجوار السوق الشرقي، دخلنا في شجار.
So it was you.
إذن أنت كنت أنت.
That scrawny,
ذلك النحيل،
dark-skinned poor kid from back then.
طفل فقير ذو بشرة داكنة من ذلك الزمان.
Yes.
نعم.
I finally made something of myself.
لقد حققتُ أخيراً شيئاً في نفسي.
I owe it all to General Su.
أدين بكل ذلك للجنرال سو.
Back then, during the chaos of war, my parents died amid the turmoil.
في ذلك الوقت، خلال فوضى الحرب، توفي والداي وسط الاضطرابات.
If General Su had not led his troops to wipe out the bandits,
لو لم يقُد الجنرال سو قواته للقضاء على قطاع الطرق،
and save us common folk,
وأنقذنا نحن عامة الناس،
I would have been dead long ago.
لكنت مت منذ زمن بعيد.
General Su was a rare kind of good commander.
كان الجنرال سو قائداً جيداً من نوع نادر.
He never sought credit and never disturbed the people.
لم يسعَ قط إلى الحصول على التقدير ولم يزعج الناس قط.
Everything he did was for the sake of the people.
كل ما فعله كان من أجل مصلحة الناس.
Su Changji?
سو تشانغجي؟
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
It really was him.
كان هو بالفعل.
I could not be mistaken.
لا يمكن أن أكون مخطئاً.
What did you see?
ماذا رأيت؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
Perhaps my eyes deceived me.
ربما خدعتني عيناي.
You must be hungry. I will get you a bun.
لا بد أنك جائع. سأحضر لك كعكة.
Wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
Go, now.
انطلق الآن.
Who goes there?
من يذهب إلى هناك؟
We are Cangzhou shadow guards. Ordered to protect young lady.
نحن حراس الظل في تسانغتشو. أُمرنا بحماية الشابة.
Protect me?
هل تحميني؟
In our current state, who would still...
في وضعنا الحالي، من سيظل...
Because of the jade pendant at Madam's neck.
بسبب قلادة اليشم التي كانت على رقبة السيدة.
The jade pendant?
قلادة اليشم؟
Mother.
الأم.
What is so special about this pendant?
ما الذي يميز هذه القلادة؟
This pendant was once a pair,
كان هذا القلادة في الأصل زوجًا،
carved from a single piece of fine jade,
منحوتة من قطعة واحدة من اليشم الفاخر،
then split in two,
ثم ينقسم إلى قسمين،
to signify never being parted.
للدلالة على عدم الفراق أبداً.
Mother.
الأم.
Remember this.
تذكر هذا.
No matter what happens,
بغض النظر عما يحدث،
you must live on.
يجب أن تستمر في الحياة.
No...
لا...
This pendant
هذا القلادة
will protect you.
سوف يحميك.
Mother.
الأم.
So you knew this day would come.
إذن كنت تعلم أن هذا اليوم سيأتي.
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
We must leave at once.
يجب أن نغادر فوراً.
No.
لا.
I want to see for myself
أريد أن أرى ذلك بنفسي
who it is
من هو؟
so eager to send me to my mother.
كانوا حريصين جداً على إرسالي إلى والدتي.
That is not the truth.
هذا ليس صحيحاً.
What happened back then likely hides another story.
من المحتمل أن ما حدث في ذلك الوقت يخفي قصة أخرى.
Another story?
قصة أخرى؟
Yuwen Que led troops to slaughter my entire family.
قاد يوين كيو قواته لذبح عائلتي بأكملها.
What is there left to explain?
ما الذي تبقى لشرحه؟
It was not so.
لم يكن الأمر كذلك.
Your mother was called a boat courtesan,
كانت والدتك تُلقب بعاهرة القوارب،
but in truth, she was a favored consort of the Emperor of Cangzhou.
لكن في الحقيقة، كانت إحدى المحظيات المفضلة لدى إمبراطور تسانغتشو.
Prince Yuwen Que
الأمير يوين كيو
was not your mother's true enemy.
لم يكن عدو والدتك الحقيقي.
Impossible.
مستحيل.
But I saw him with my own eyes...
لكنني رأيته بأم عيني...
Your mother was framed back then,
لقد تم تلفيق التهمة لوالدتك في ذلك الوقت.
that is why...
ولهذا السبب...
Could it be that all these years,
هل يُعقل أن كل هذه السنوات،
I have been hating the wrong person?
هل كنت أكره الشخص الخطأ؟